<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homepage on Dr. Himani Arora</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homepage on Dr. Himani Arora</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/sections/aboutme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sections/aboutme/</guid>
      <description>I received my Ph.D. in Physics from TU Dresden (Germany) in 2020 and am currently working as a postdoctoral researcher at Helmholtz-Zentrum Dresden-Rossendorf (HZDR). Prior to that, I completed my Bachelor’s in Metallurgical Engineering from IIT-BHU (India) and Master’s in Advanced Functional Materials, jointly from the University of Augsburg (Germany) and the Institut polytechnique de Grenoble (France) under Erasmus Mundus Scholarship Program.
My research is focused on the characterization and integration of nanoscale materials and their heterostructures into electronic devices (transistors, photodetectors, and sensors).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/sections/awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sections/awards/</guid>
      <description>10/2020 Best Student Award in the entire Ph.D. Program at the Annual Workshop of IHRS NanoNet (International Helmholtz Research School for Nanoelectronic Networks).   08/2018 1st prize in Scientific Image Competition organized by cfaed (Center for Advancing Electronics Dresden). The winning image was an optical microscopic image of a field-effect transistor build on 2D polymers (Link to announcement).   06/2018 3rd prize in Science Slam on “2D or not 2D” organized by Technische Sammlungen Dresden in collaboration with Silicon Saxony e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/sections/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sections/contact/</guid>
      <description>Email: himani.arora.06@gmail.com
Github: himani-arora-ha
ORCID: Visit my profile here
Google Scholar: Visit my profile here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/sections/news/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sections/news/</guid>
      <description>04/2020 Optics and Photonics News published a report on our MOF photodetectors.   04/2020 Laserfocusworld and Science Daily  reported on our MOF photodetectors.   03/2020 Our paper on MOF photodetectors is featured on the back cover of Advanced Materials.   01/2020 phys.org and EurekAlert! referred to our paper on encapsulation of air-sensitive 2D materials.   10/2018 Nanowerk and Technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/sections/outreach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sections/outreach/</guid>
      <description>  Mentoring Students
  &amp;hellip; Test
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/sections/personal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sections/personal/</guid>
      <description>I am fluent in Hindi, English, and German.
Since 2017, I am part of the amazing Peace Slam Project: We are a group of young internationals in Dresden and pitch our idea of peace, tolerance, and intercultural understanding to diverse audiences, for example at schools, local companies, and cultural festivals. One highlight was in 2018, where I slammed, in German, in front of more than 1,000 people at Palaissommer Dresden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/sections/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sections/projects/</guid>
      <description>Investigation of Temperature Dependent Electronic Properties of Encapsulated Black Phosphorus.
  Development of Highly Stable and Sensitive Black Phosphorus Based Gas Sensors as well as Black Phosphorus Based Reconfigurable 2D Circuits.
  Investigation of (opto)electronic properties of π–d conjugated 2D MOFs.
  Characterization of Germanium Nanowires (sub-40 nm) Using a Reliable Hall-bar Configuration.
  Fabrication and Characterization of p–n Junctions Based on Implanted Germanium Nanowires for Photodetection Applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/sections/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sections/test/</guid>
      <description>.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
